Diego Rivera

Full Stack Developer

Address Sacramento, CA, 95814

Phone (916) 508-0261

E-mail diegorivera1110@gmail.com

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/diego-rivera-

67684a225

WWW https://zety.com/profile/e404-

220402103657/658

Meticulous inventory professional with 5 years of experience initiating and managing cycle counts and reprocessing programs. Skillful in collaborating with other departments to keep necessary items available. Expert in coordinating inventory systems.

I now have sights on learning as much about **Software Development** and switch careers into Tech. In order to help make this career change I am currently enrolled in a Coding Bootcamp through UC Davis that will be providing certification on completion in August of 2022.

Skills

HTML expertise	Excellent
CSS proficiency	Very Good
JavaScript programming	Very Good
JQuery	Very Good
Materialize Framework	Excellent
Bootstrap Framework	Excellent
Node.js	Very Good
MySQL	Very Good
NoSQL	Very Good
MongoDB	Very Good
Git	Excellent
React	Very Good

Transferable Skills

- Critical Thinking
- Patient
- Motivated
- Strong Written/Oral Communicator
- Very Organized
- Great Collaborator
- Very Adaptable/Flexible
- Keen Attention to Details
- Self-Sufficient
- Problem-Solver

Education

2022-03 - Current

Full Stack Developer Certification: Full-Stack Software Engineering

University of California - Davis - Davis, CA

Some College (No Degree): Philosophy And Religious Studies

Pasadena City College - Pasadena, CA

Some College (No Degree)

Sacramento City College - Sacramento, CA

Work History

2021-02 - Current

Inventory Control Lead

Flash Global Logistics, West Sacramento, California

- Addressed internal supply problems head-on and developed creative solutions to prevent delays and missed targets.
- Managed complex projects as directed by leadership, delivering positive outcomes within time and budget constraints.
- Implemented organizational systems to optimize product placement and operational productivity.
- Kept documentation and records accurate and up-to-date with latest data to prevent errors in processing or delivery.
- Recorded information, shortages and discrepancies to keep records current and accurate.
- Completed daily cycle counts to maintain accuracy of records.

- Input data in FlashTrac & Microsoft Excel sheets to create updated status reports for quick reference of project progress and deadlines.
- Audited and corrected discrepancies in inventory numbers.
- Input data in FlashTrac to create updated status reports for quick reference of project progress and deadlines.

Reliable Parts, West Sacramento, California

- Addressed internal supply problems head-on and developed creative solutions to prevent delays and missed targets.
- Kept documentation and records accurate and up-to-date with latest data to prevent errors in processing or delivery.
- Verified contents of inventory loads against Bills of Lading.
- Completed physical inventory counts each month.
- Managed inventory team to achieve optimal productivity and inventory control.
- Maintained and organized inventory receipts and processed changes to reduce process lags.
- Worked with supervisors and team members to understand supply needs and bring levels within desired tolerances.
- Performed data entry and completed proper paperwork.
- Coordinated, collected and maintained vendor and organizational records.
- Recorded adjustments, pallet audits and tracked discrepancies.

2019-01 - 2020-06 Inbound Team Lead

BabyList, Sacramento, CA

- Compared shipping orders and invoices against contents received to verify accuracy.
- Worked with inventory managers and unloaders to plan deliveries.
- Investigated and adopted optimal shipping and receiving strategies by selecting best carriers, routes and methods to minimize costs and enhance schedules.
- Coordinated warehouse organization scheme and product placements.
- Organized storage areas to optimize materials movements and minimize labor hours.
- Maintained accurate computer records of materials weights, bill amounts and identified variances.
- Unloaded pallets and deliveries and organized products in warehouse.
- Mastered warehouse computer system and trained other team members in software operation.
- Corresponded with carrier representatives to make arrangements and provide instructions for shipment and delivery of orders.
- Packed, secured, labeled and applied postage to materials to prepare items for shipment.
- Processed required paperwork to expedite handling of shipped and received goods.

- Handled day-to-day shipping and receiving overseeing more than 1,000 packages per day.
- Rejected damaged items, recorded shortages and corresponded with shippers to rectify issues.
- Utilized forklift or pallet truck to load, unload, transport and store goods.
- Verified orders by comparing names and quantity of items packaged with shipping documents.
- Entered orders into inventory computer database system.

2017-08 - 2018-01 Warehouse Associate

Western Powersports, Fresno, CA

- Inspected incoming and outgoing shipments to verify accuracy and prevent errors.
- Used hand-held devices and computers to record and monitor inventory levels and completed audits to uncover and address inaccuracies.
- Recorded daily incoming delivery information and obtained vendor signature on delivery tickets.
- Recorded information, shortages and discrepancies to keep records current and accurate.
- Volunteered to assist with projects, demonstrating willingness to learn new tasks and increase skill levels.
- Operated PC and RF-based computer systems for inventory management.
- Handled daily customer service aspects and maintained positive relationships with external customers and freight partners.
- Entered quantity received against purchase order in computer system.
- Checked packages and merchandise for damage and notified vendors.
- Labeled and accurately moved customer orders to meet shipment timetables and minimize errors.